Hussain Alnakhli, Junior Web Developer

Ontario, Canada, 6138932003, mah.hussaina@gmail.com

LINKS	linkedin.com/in/hussainalnakhli, github.com/HussAA, HussainAlnakhli.com		
PROFILE	During my IT program, I discovered a passion for web development, which led me to specialize in React. Since then, I have dedicated myself to becoming a skilled web developer by creating multiple websites and expanding my knowledge through online courses. I have always been able to adapt myself to whatever I put my mind to.		
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY			
Jul 2024 — Present	Full Stack Web Developer, Tech Axis Solutions (Founder)	Riyadh, Saudi Arabia	
	 Founded a software company with currently 2 employees with three main divisions: a local services marketplace platform, a CRM platform for tailoring stores, and a department dedicated to collaborating with businesses to create custom software solutions, 		
Jan 2022 — Present	Junior Web Developer, Solv-it	Remote	
	 Currently working on a complex local service marketplace web app for booking services like home cleaning, using Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, NestJS, REST API, PostgreSQL, AWS, and Figma for designing. I created several React auto-detail websites. Built a custom admin website for a Middle Eastern tailoring clothing store to manage customer information and orders. Tech-Stack used: React, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, GraphQL, and Strapi. 		
May 2023 — Aug 2023	Full Stack Web Developer Internship, CompuFix Kingston	Kingston, Ontario	
	 Developed backend website feature, Heatmap, using React, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Maps JavaScript API. Implement changes to backend Strapi website, ensuring seamless integration and functionality. 		
Jan 2023 — Apr 2023	IT Specialist Co-op, CompuFix Kingston	Kingston, Ontario	
	 Diagnose and repair hardware/software issues on desktops and Apple products, ensuring optimal performance. Implement necessary changes on WordPress website, enhancing user experience and functionality. 		
May 2021 — Dec 2021	Amazon FBA Seller, Amazon	Remote	
	 Managed product sourcing, listing creation, inventory, and marketing for an Amazon FBA business. Sold products to customers in the USA, Mexico, and Canada. 		
Oct 2020 — Nov 2021	Busser, The Keg Steakhouse	Kingston, Canada	
	 Assisted with clearing and setting tables, ensuring a clean and organized dining area. Supported servers and maintained a high level of customer service in a busy restaurant environment. 		
Jan 2019 — Sep 2020	Shopify E-commerce Business Owner, Shopify	Remote	
	 Built and managed a Shopify store specializing in fitness products, handling global sales and customer service. Coordinated with Asian manufacturers for product sourcing and shipping. Executed social media marketing strategies, including Facebook and Google ads. 		
Sep 2014 — Aug 2015	Youtuber, Google	Remote	
	 Created and managed video content on YouTube, including scripting, filming, editing, and engaging with fans. Achieved 2 million views through high-quality content and active audience interaction. 		

EDUCATION			
Sep 2024 — Dec 2024	Computer Science - Certificate, Harvard		Remote
	 C Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms SQL, Flask, Cybersecurity. 	s, Python, Artificial Inte	elligence, Web Development,
Sep 2021 — Apr 2023	Computer Systems Technician, St. Lawrence	College	Kingston, Ontario
	 Managed and optimized networking, databases, a Configured and maintained AWS and Azure envir Conducted security audits and implemented ethi Provided technical support for computer hardwa 	ronments, improving clo cal security practices, red	oud infrastructure performance. ducing vulnerabilities.
PROJECTS			
Jun 2024 — Present	Local Services Marketplace		Canada
	 Allows users to effortlessly browse, book, and pay for a wide range of services, from home cleaning and car repairs to delivery and personal care. Tech-Stack: Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, NestJS, REST API, PostgreSQL, AWS, and Figma for designing. 		
Jul 2024 — Jul 2024	Static React Web App		Riyadh, Saudi Arabia
	• I developed a responsive web app for TURNERY, a company specializing in machine parts sales and gearbox maintenance. Tech-Stack: Figma, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Framer Motion, and Email.js		
Apr 2024 — Apr 2024	Todo React Native App		Remote
	Built a simple to-do app using React Native for managing tasks.		
Jan 2023 — Jun 2024	Auto Detailing Web Apps		Canada
	 I created several React auto-detail websites using: , Email.js, Tawk.to, JavaScript. 	Gatsby.js, React, Tails	wind CSS, HTML/CSS-
SKILLS	React Next.js Tailwind CSS	Shopify / WordPres	s / Wix
	Node.js JavaScript	Microsoft Office	
	Docker AWS PostgreSQL	Software & Hardwa	re Repairs
	NestJS Express.js REST API	Google Business/Ad	lSense/Ads
	Figma	Facebook Advertises	ments
	Python	Ability to Work in a Team	
	Linux	Adaptability Leade Communication Sk	
LANGUAGES	English (Fluent)	Arabic (Native)	
CERTIFICATIONS ANI	D CLEARANCES		
Oct 2024	Transport Canada level A security clearance		Ottawa, ON

REFERENCES

References available upon request